

Software Engineer dmtrmsc@gmail.com +3530852023712 Ireland, Cork

**Date of birth** 29/03/1993

Nationality Ukrainian

# Dmytró Kulykov

### **Profile**

I'm an Engineer with 6 years of experience in quality assurance, 4 of which are related to automation. In addition, I was engaged in the development of simple features and load testing of the service in production. Now I am learning the Java language and improving my English, considering employment options related to previous experience, and I am also ready to open up new areas in the field of IT. I have a work permit in Ireland.

# **Employment**

### Junior Engineer at Avito Tech

11/2020-04/2022

The Antimonolit team (architecture cluster)

Despite the fact that most of the code has already been transferred to microseries, of which there are more than 1 thousand (\*), you can't do without a monolith. The global task of the team is to facilitate the monolith, accelerate the deployment, help other teams with the removal of tests from the monolith that others forgot to transfer, as well as to deal with shifts and solve major problems related to the work of the entire Avito.

- organized the testing process in the team
- contributed to reducing the load on the monolith integration API by transferring test methods to the gRPC protocol (the campaign is carried out directly to the service without integration), accelerated authorization for e2e tests by substituting cookies
- moved more than 200 tests and 40 helper methods from the monolith to 4 different microservices with refactoring and pull request launch settings.
- completed more than 15 tasks of simple backend tasks from the general backlog (creating endpoints, transferring logic to a new service on Go, deleting old code)
- set up non-functional metrics and alerts for service in production
- helped product teams with testing complex scenarios, for example, authorization and transfer of the ad card to react and writing autotests.
   As a result, after the 4th attempt of correction and complete regression, the ad card flew into production.

### Middle QA Engineer at Avito

07/2018-11/2020

The Support Systems team (trust&safety cluster)

Support systems, to put it very briefly, are a product team engaged in the development of a user-friendly request service (calls, emails, requests

# Links

LinkedIn
Facebook
Telegram
Github

Download this CV

# **Skills**

Git	.3/5
SQL	. 2/5
PHP	.3/5
Selenium	. 4/5
Cypress	.3/5
CI/CD	.3/5
Grafana	. 2/5
TeamCity	. 3/5
Docker	.3/5
Agile Testing	. 4/5
Peformance Testing	.3/5
Sentry	. 3/5
Kibana	. 2/5
Linux/Unix	. 2/5
API Testing	. 4/5
A/B Testing	. 3/5
Manual Testing	. 4/5
Functional Testing	. 4/5

# Languages

Russian	Native speaker
English	Very good command
Ukranian	Highly proficient

from applications and chats) and a system for processing these requests, including a prioritization and administration system.

- work with documentation: updated unit test model (more than 600 test cases)
- · implementation of agile testing
- participation in the development process: participation in grooming, planning, discovery, and offering their own options for solving problems. And also at the time of these meetings, a draft was already being formed with a set of scenarios for testing. This draft was written into the task, and even before the task was completed, the developers could see critical scenarios that should be taken into account when implementing this task.
- control over the development process: monitored the life cycle of the defect and suggested to the team things that should be improved.
- research work: I reproduced bugs based on information from Sentry, conducted exploratory testing of previously unknown functionality, sorted out difficult-to-reproduce bugs based on auxiliary data received from users of our system and reproduced them.
- · testing of chatbots and speech recognition
- acting as a release manager: performed the functions of a release manager, rolling out features for a percentage using canary releases
- carrying out load testing: I prepared the environment and ran closed/open tests to determine the Capacity in a special performance environment and then repeated the tests in production. Based on the results, I wrote a report with data attached (logs, information from Grafana) and made assumptions because of what a bottleneck could form and what could be improved.

#### Optional:

I served as a team leader for a team of 6 from October 2019 to July 2020.

### Middle QA Engineer at Rucenter

05/2017-06/2018

Creation of test scenarios, preparation of a test plan, preparation of test benches, verification of defect fixes, maintenance of test documentation, analysis of errors in log files

### Software tester at Bifit

04/2016-05/2017

Functional testing of web applications through the user interface. Working with test documentation. Deployment of a test bank test bench, testing releases. Testing hardware devices with cryptography.

# **Education**

### Engineer, Moscow Aviation Institute, Moscow

09/2010-03/2016

Information systems and technologies

# Courses

PHP for Beginners at Udemy 09/2019—12/2019

**Java Foundation Cource at ecollege.ie** 06/2022

### **Books**

Agile testing

**PHP 7** 

Clean Code: A Handbook of Agile Software

Docker